Matt Schwartz

ohmattschwartz@gmail.com 551.265.2746 github.com/ohmattschwartz MattSchwartz.tech

About Me

After seven years in the music industry in Los Angeles, I completed The Iron Yard's Front-End Engineering course where I studied JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS. Currently seeking a web development position with an emphasis on design, client interaction, and user-experience optimization.

Education

The Iron Yard - Certificate in Front-End Engineering St. Petersburg, FL, July 18 - October 7, 2016

- · An immersive, 12-week course in Front-End Web Development
- Created 35 projects using HTML/CSS, JSX, Bootstrap, Affinity Designer
- Learned JavaScript, REACT, HTML, CSS, SCSS, SASS

Skidmore College - Bachelor of Science in Theater/Political Science Saratoga Springs, NY, 2004 - 2008

Employment

Check I'm Here

Metrics Dashboard Developer and Analyst St. Petersburg, FL (Contract- Ongoing)

- →Access various data and metrics from various web API's.
- →Use Node to create a landing area for fetched data.
- → Use Angular.Js to build front-end Dashboard for company use.

The Shop Productions

Development Assistant

Studio City, CA (2014-2015)

- **▶**Created content for Pilot-Pitch presentations. **Extensive Writing Required**.
- → Designed and edited "First-Look" videos for network development meetings.
- ➡ Researched/scouted shooting locations for pitch videos.

Kingdom 2 Music

Music Director

Los Angeles, CA (2008-2014)

- ⇒Supervised all licensing and music placements for film and TV projects.
- ► Marketing: Designed and wrote all press releases and newsletters.
- **▶** Designed layout of company website.
- → Delegated tasks, served as liaison between clients and CEO/staff and CEO.
- → Generated business opportunities via networking lunches, calls, events.

Tech Skills

JavaScript (JSX)
REACT
HTML5
Affinity Designer
Microsoft Office
Sass/CSS3
Final Draft
Final Cut Pro
Sibelius
Logic Pro

Skills

Web Development
UI Design
Teamwork
Leadership
Sales experience
Copywriting
Songwriting
Cold-Calls

Interests

Songwriting
Theater
Improv Comedy
Travel
Film/TV
Piano
Design
Reading/Writing Fiction

Activities

Improv Comedy Coach at American Stage. Training Online in: Affinity Designer WordPress. Volunteer/Writer at TheStudio@620.